# Jinal Jain

Currently: Studio 1317, Fusion Tower, Rupert street, Bristol - BS1 2AS Home Address: Thane, Maharashtra, India

+44 7951655844 / +91 9619494692 | jinaljain26@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/jinal-jain-08787882

### **PROFILE**

Currently studying MSc Psychology of Education from the University of Bristol, UK. Throughout my academic journey, I have regularly engaged in volunteer work and worked with special needs children at schools, older adults with Parkinson's disease and trained under a reputed career counsellor in Mumbai. I am very passionate about career planning and reducing barriers to employment for people with disabilities and I look forward to increasing my on-field experience.

# **EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS**

<u>University of Bristol - MSc Psychology of Education</u> Introduction to educational enquiry (85); Cognition and learning (82); Statistics in Education (66) 2020

• Currently directed my dissertation effort towards understanding the perspectives of the career advisors and students with/without disabilities regarding the transition from education to employment.

<u>Jai Hind College, Mumbai - BA Psychology</u> Clinical Perspectives on Psychological Disorders (88); Organizational Psychology (86); Counselling: Theoretical Approaches (80)

- Presented a Research paper titled "Empathy and self-consciousness as factors affecting depression among Indian women". At Bombay Psychological Association Conference (2019)
- Presented a Research paper titled "Decision making & problem-solving Life skills as a Satisfaction indicator in late adolescents" at Indian Association of Life Skills Education International conference (2018)

Jai Hind College, Mumbai - Junior College Passed HSC Arts with 88.77%

2016

St. John the Baptist High School, Thane Passed SSC with 89.60%

2014

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Supply Teacher Assistant | TeacherActive, Bristol**

**Dec 2019 to Mar 2020** 

TeacherActive is one of the largest specialist education recruitment companies in the UK.

- Provided extra support by guiding and monitoring the tasks at hand of the primary pupils with special needs
- · Preparing and tidying the classroom
- · Helped with classroom prep, board displays and the planning of activities
- Dealt with immediate issues like injuries that may arise and handling them in the most appropriate way

### **Internship Trainee | Holistree, Mumbai**

Jun 2019 to Sep 2019

Holistree is a Unique Teen Support System & Career Designers. They work with the belief that every child is unique in his/her own way.

- Training involved tasks and real-life projects which focused on developing counselling skills like observation, listening, questioning, reflecting and paraphrasing.
- Counselled pupils aged 21 and 18 through 8 one-to-one sessions (under supervision), helping them to understand their career values, interests and unique skills.

Manufacturers of Electrostatic Powder Coating Paints

• Bridging communication with production team regarding issues pertaining to general welfare, analysing the work culture, generally observing the admin staff.

#### Intern | Parkinson's Disease and Movement Disorder Society, Mumbai

Apr 2017 to May 2017

- Helped out at the support groups by providing physical and practical assistance during Yoga and Physiotherapy sessions.
- Involved in the "Volunteer home visit program" which included visiting Parkinson's at home and conducting activities like physical exercises, playing games and discussing current affairs or about their hobbies, daily activities.

### Volunteer | CHILDReach, Mumbai

Feb 2017 to Aug 2017

- Conducted art and craft sessions for children with learning difficulties ranging from dyslexia, behavioural problems and ADHD to improve their dexterity, confidence and communication skills.
- Interacted with older girls about their experiences and career plans.
- Helped to arrange eligible writers to support students during exams.
- Helped during school events and assisted children during computer learning sessions.

# ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS AND RESPONSIBILITIES

**Social Rep** - during MSc Psychology of Education BPS course at the University of Bristol. Organized a couple social events and held online activities.

**Headed the Logistics team** (25 members) for an intercollege college PsycInsight fest (2018-19) held by Jai Hind College, Mumbai which had a footfall of 500 to 600 people.

**President of the Rotaract Club of Thane Skyline** (2017-18) - organized community service projects like Slum painting, teaching English to vernacular medium school children and blood donation camps.

**Hold a certificate in Elementary Entrepreneurship** led by NEN faculty leaders at Jai Hind College, Mumbai (2016).

**Hold a certificate in International relations Level 1** organized by the History Department of Jai Hind College, Mumbai (2016).